遅刻
って もう夏休みだっけ
I'm gonna be late!
ほら りのん
もう 邪魔しないで
Oh yeah, it's summer vacation now.
Hey, Rinon!
だめだってば くすぐったいから
Don't get in the way!
あ おはよう 海人君
Stop that!
お おはようございます
It tickles!
Morning, Kaito!
前略 姉上様
Good morning!
不肖の弟です
夏休みの初日から
やばいです
Dear Sister,
理性を保てるかどうか
it's your humbled brother.
正直 自信がありません
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.Kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
It's the first day of summer vacation, and I'm already in trouble.
I don't really think...
I can stay...
sane at this rate.
Kaito...
海人君
Yes? What is it?
はい 何でしょう
Did you buy that camera?
そのカメラって買ったの
It looks pretty old.
にしてはかなり古い感じがするけど
I found it in our shed.
家の納屋にあったんです
Maybe it belonged to my dead grandfather.
多分 死んだ爺ちゃんのだと思うんですけど
I like it for some reason.
何となく 気に入って
ねえねえ どうやって使うの
How do you use it?
It's pretty simple.
簡単ですよ
You put in this film, focus the lens, and then press the shutter button.
このフィルムをセットして
レンズのピントにあわせて シャッターを押すだけ
あ あの
Um...
何
What?
You're really close.
近い
夏休みの初日から
It's only the first day of break,
yet you're already making your move on him.
だいぶ フランクになってきたわね
That's not true!
そ そんなことはありません
'Sup.
ちーっす
Hello there.
こんにちは
What are you doing, Kaito?
何してるの 海人君
Stretching, I guess.
柔軟かな
All right, let's get the good times rolling and make this movie.
さあ 楽しい楽しい映画制作を始めましょう
Castle Park
Hey, Kai.
なあ 海 今日は 何を撮るんだ
What are we shooting today?
No idea.
知らないよ
Lemon's in charge of the script.
脚本担当とは 檸檬先輩だろ
Never fear.
大丈夫よ 今日の分の本は出来上がってるわ
The script for today is done.
Just for today?
今日の分
I write my scripts Hong Kong style.
私の制作スタイルは香港式
今日撮る映画の内容は
I figure out what we're going to film the morning of the shoot.
その日の朝に決めるの
So you're just winging it.
それは 行き当たりばったりというんじゃ
着替え終わったよ
We're done changing!
わあ すげえ 似合ってますよ
Wow! You look great in that!
先輩
Really?
そ そうかな
Where did you get that outfit?
どうしたんです この衣装
It looks really expensive.
かなりお金がかかってるような
I asked the school's cosplay club for help.
学校のコスプレ部に協力を依頼したの
There's a cosplay club?
そんな部 あったっけ
I dunno...
さあ
どうかな 変じゃない
So how is it?
It looks great on you! I'm serious!
似合ってますよ 本当に
That's good.
なら いいんだけど
After the female protagonist
lands on Earth, fate guides her
toward an Earthling boy.
After the female protagonist
lands on Earth, fate guides her
toward an Earthling boy.
After the female protagonist
lands on Earth, fate guides her
toward an Earthling boy.
After the female protagonist
lands on Earth, fate guides her
toward an Earthling boy.
After the female protagonist
lands on Earth, fate guides her
toward an Earthling boy.
Today we're filming the scene where the heroine first meets the guy.
今日撮る内容はヒロインが初めて男の子と出会うシーンよ
So it's a love story?
恋愛ものなんだ
That could work.
すごくいいかも
Also,
ちなみに ヒロインは宇宙人という設定だから
the heroine is an alien.
は 斬新だな
That's pretty avant-garde.
それで あの衣装なんだ
That explains why she's wearing that.
After the heroine lands on Earth,
地球に降り立ったヒロインが
地球人の少年と運命的な出会いを果たす
she has a fateful encounter with a boy.
We'll be ad-libbing all the lines.
台詞はすべてアドリブで
I leave the rest to the director.
あとは監督に任せるわ
That's a lot to ask.
無茶苦茶ですよ
And who'll be playing the Earth boy?
それで 地球人の少年役は
I've got the camera to take care of.
俺は カメラを回さなきゃならないから
Does it have to be me, then?
必然的に俺か
That would be great! I'd love that!
いいと思う すごくいいと思う
Hold on. I was just planning on helping out behind the scenes.
待ってくれよ 俺は裏方を手伝うつもりで
Ishigaki.
石垣君
状況に応じて対応する
Everyone has to adapt to change.
The set is a living creature.
そう 現場は生き物なのよ
Implying you'd know.
知ったような口を
Sounds good to me!
いいじゃない 貴月先輩みたいな美人の相手ができるんだから
You'll get to work with somebody as pretty as Takatsuki.
きっと一生忘れられない思い出になるわよ
I'm sure it'll be something to remember.
These are supposed to be the best days of my life?
俺の人生 ここがピークかよ
いいから いいから
Don't be shy!
You're enjoying this, aren't you?
お前 楽しんでるだろ
Of course I'm not.
そんなことないない
I'll be playing an alien...
宇宙人の役
どうしました
What's wrong?
Nothing at all.
ううん 何でもないから
よしっと
All right.
海人君 準備 整ったよ
We're set, Kaito.
Okay, then...
よし じゃあ
Action.
よい スタート
So this is Earth...
こ ここが地球
開発レベルＦの辺境惑星
A planet in Stage F of development on the edge of civilization.
They've just started exploring outer space.
宇宙開発は始まったばかりで
The only place they've reached with a manned craft is their satellite, which they call the Moon.
有人で到達したのは 月と呼ばれている
この星の衛星のみ
Her lines are on the mark.
結構 セリフがリアルですね
たどたどしいけど
The delivery's a little stiff, though.
Next: Enter, Ishigaki.
次 石垣君 入るわよ
Okay.
ええっす
わ 私はこの星に来たのには 理由がある
I came to this planet for a reason.
わ 私は この場所で
This is where...
There you are!
そこにいたんですか
Who are you?
あ あなたは
I've been looking for you!
あなたを探していたんです
私を
For me?
すでに出会ってる設定になりましたよ
That makes it seem like they've met before.
It's fine.
いいから
I've been watching you all this time.
ずっと 見ていました あなた
つまり あなたは宇宙人だ
I know you're an alien!
そして 俺はメン?イン?ブラック
And I'm from the Men in Black.
Not the Men in Black!
メ メン?イン?ブラックは
いやあああ
はい カット
Okay, cut!
Excellent work, both of you.
素晴らしかったわよ イチカ 石垣君
I just got into it all of a sudden.
いや つい熱くなっちゃいました
The male lead just died...
相手役 死んじゃった
How is this gonna work?
いいのか これで
先輩 すごいアドリブでしたね
You did a really good job ad-libbing.
あふふふふ 何となく
Yeah, it just came to me.
So what now?
で 今は
映画の内容が変わったから
Now that the lead is dead, we have to wait for Lemon to come up with a new idea.
檸檬先輩のアイデア待ちです
なんでも ヒロインは逃亡開始
I expect your character will try to escape with the MIB in hot pursuit.
メン?イン?ブラックによる 激しい追跡劇が始まるとか何とか
へえ
What do you think?
ここ どうです
ここの景色 この先に池もあるんです
About the scenery here.
There's a pond that way as well.
ほら 先輩 前に言ってたじゃないですか
You told us that you're looking for a certain place.
行きたい場所があるって
木があって 池があって
There were trees, a lake...
何の特徴もない場所なんだけど
There's nothing special about it.
That kinda makes it hard to find.
それじゃ 探しようが
そうだよね
Yeah.
でも 行きたいの
But I want to find it anyway.
Kaito... You remembered that?
海人君 覚えていてくれたんだ
I chose a place that seemed similar, but I guess this isn't it.
それっぽい場所をチョイスしたんですけど
違ってるみたいですね
すみません
Sorry.
No, I'm grateful.
そんなことない
ありがとう
Thank you.
I'll keep looking.
また 探しますから
この この このこのこのこの
Oh, you...
SOBA NOODLES
You, you, you...
Hey, what?
ちょっと なんですか やめてください
Stop it!
You, you...
Bring them something to drink, Kanna.
柑菜 イチカ先輩たちに飲み物持っててやれよ
SOBA NOODLES
ああ なんだよ
What?
I've been wondering for a while...
前々から気になってたんだけど
Tetsuro, do you know how I feel?
哲郎 私の気持ち 知ってる
It's quite obvious.
バレバレだからな
いつから
When did you realize?
I don't even know.
忘れた
Will you help me?
もしかして 応援してくれるの
Of course I'd help my childhood friend.
幼馴染だからな
ありがとう
Thanks.
哲郎も できたら 教えて
Tell me if you have someone!
I'll help you too!
応援するから
That's not gonna happen.
そりゃ 無理だな
That hurts, Kitahara.
痛いわ 北原さん
Sorry, I sort of spaced out...
すみません あの ぼうっとしてて 私
I'm done.
できたわ 撮影再開よ
Let's start filming again.
Vale
of
Crimson
Leaves
The female lead returns to her spaceship to escape her pursuers
追手から逃れるため
ヒロインは宇宙船に戻り
and meets up with a friend.
そこで 仲間と合流するの
A friend?
仲間
Who's gonna play the part?
誰がやるんです
この子よ
This cutie.
りのん
Rinon?!
いつの間に
When did she...
This is going to be the bio-terminal of the spaceship.
この子は宇宙船の生体端末という設定よ
I expect great things from you, Ichika.
よろしく頼むわね イチカ
Um, okay...
ええ まあ
では 始めましょう
Let's get cracking.
We're ready here, Lemon.
檸檬先輩 準備が整いました
了解よ
Roger that.
Who's the director again?
もう 誰が監督だか 分からねえよ
Cameraman, ready?
カメラ 準備は
I'm ready!
はい 整ってます
よい スタート
And action.
They're after me, Rinon! Help me!
りのん 追手が来てるの
お願い 私を助けて
In your dreams!
そうは行かないな
あ あの ど どうして
What are you doing...
兄さんの仇は この 俺が取る
I shall avenge...
my brother!
はい カット
Okay, cut.
Great work, Ichika, Ishigaki, Rinon.
素晴らしかったわよ イチカ 石垣君 りのん
何勝手に乱入してんだよ
Why did you just run in there?!
役者としてのサガかな
I guess it's just my actor's spirit.
You're getting too into this.
その気になりすぎだろう
あの これから どうするんですか
Um, what's next?
You should know.
決まってるわ これから 考えるのよ
We think.
You have nowhere to stay?
住む場所がない
そ そうなの
Exactly!
Why don't you stay at my place?
だったら 俺の家に来ませんか
I'm living alone, and there are empty rooms.
俺 一人暮らしだし 家に 部屋 余ってますから
Really?
本当に
Yeah!
ありがとう 本当に ありがとう
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Um...
はい カット
Okay, cut!
We're finally getting into the story now.
ようやく本筋に戻りましたね
Indeed.
お疲れさん
Good work.
When did I become an actor anyway?
つうか 俺いつの間にか役者やってるし カメラやってねえし
Who cares?
いいじゃんか イチカ先輩の相手役なんだから
You get to be who Ichika ends up with.
お前 まさか わざと
Did you do this on purpose?
どうでしょう
Who's to say?
Kaito's become the male lead now.
海人君が相手役になっちゃいましたね
Seems that way.
結局ね
これから 二人はどうなると思います
How do you think things are gonna play out between you two?
えっ 分からないかな
I don't really know.
なら 先輩は どういう展開になればいいと思いますか
Well, how do you think it should end?
幸せになれればいいと思うけど
It'd be nice if they could end up happy.
It would.
ですよね
You are the lead.
Episode Five
そうですよね
It would, wouldn't it?
In the end, Lemon was both cameraman and director.
結局 監督もカメラも 檸檬先輩だし
What's gonna happen now?
これから どうなるんだか
Sorry for taking a bath first.
お先に失礼しました
No, it's fine.
That was a nice bath.
いいお湯でした
Are we filming again tomorrow?
で 明日も撮影
みたいですよ 檸檬先輩次第ですけど
Seems that way.
It all depends on Lemon, though.
What are you doing?
なに
Lemon told me to get as many scenes as I could of the heroine getting used to life on Earth.
檸檬先輩に言われたんです
ヒロインが地球の生活に馴染んで行くシーンを
できるだけ撮っておけって
こんなとこ 撮らないでいいです
You don't have to film me right now.
By the way...
あのね
Yeah?
はい
About the movie....
映画の話なんだけど
What would you do if you found out who the heroine really was?
海人君はヒロインの正体を知ったらどうする
Lemon'll be the one to figure that out.
それは 檸檬先輩が考えることで
Well, what would you do, personally?
海人君なら どうするか
教えて
I guess I'd think it was pretty amazing.
まあ 単純にすごいなと
Seriously though...
そういうことじゃなくて
I guess I'd ask her to take me into space with her.
宇宙に連れててもらえるかなとか
規則があるから
There are laws against that...
Huh?
You wouldn't mind being with someone from another planet?
違う星の人と一緒にいても平気
Well, as long as she doesn't ooze weird juices...
ええ 変な液体とか出さなければ
Of course not!
そんなのない
Then sure. Why not?
だったら いいんじゃないですか
It wouldn't really bug me.
別に俺は気にしませんけど
そっか
I see.
あの 先輩
Um, Ichika?
I'll make some tea.
お茶 入れてくるね
Okay.
What was that about?
先輩
何だったんだろう
Tanigawa speaking.
はい 谷川
Hey, Mio, it's me.
ああ 美桜 私
No filming today, huh?
やっぱり 撮影はなしか
この雨だもんね
On account of rain, I guess.
Yeah, sure.
うん 分かった
I'll talk to you later. See ya.
また 連絡するね
じゃあ
What were you talking about?
何の話をしてたの
Nothing.
いや 別に
Nothing really.
大したことじゃないわ
Have you gotten used to life around here, Takatsuki?
貴月先輩 ここでの生活 慣れました
Yeah, kinda.
うん もうかなり
But you know, she has some weird ideas.
でもさ 先輩 ちょっと変わってて
チョコレート味のカレーとか作るんだよ
The other day she was making chocolate-flavored curry.
えっ ダメなの
Is that weird?
Yeah, kinda.
まあ ちょっとだけ
I see.
そうなんだ
Oh yeah, I need to buy ingredients.
あっ 食材買い足さないと
Want to stop by the supermarket on the way home?
じゃあ 帰り スーパーよりますか
We're running out of tissues too.
そういえば ティッシュが少なくなってましたね
And detergent.
洗剤も
Let's stop by a pharmacy too.
だったら 薬局にも行きましょう
Sounds good.
そうね
はい どちら様
Yes, who is it?
Oh, Tanigawa?
谷川
Good morning!
こんにちは お母さんに持ってってあげなさいって言われて
My mom told me to bring this over.
They're vegetables.
野沢菜
ああ ありがとう
Thanks.
へえ こんなにたくさん
There's a lot here.
Um...
ああ えっと
Kaito, trouble!
海人君 大変
何です
What is it?
This house is pretty old.
この家古いから
I'll check the roof when it clears up.
晴れたら 屋根 見ときますよ
Sorry about that. I was just surprised.
ごめんなさい びっくりしちゃって
Well, it's not every day that this happens.
まあ あんまり ないことですから
Hey, Tanigawa!
あら 谷川さん
Sorry I didn't call before I came here.
あ お邪魔しちゃいました
Oh, it's no problem.
どうぞ どうぞ って 私が言うべきじゃないけど
Actually, it's not really my house, but...
そうだ 良かったら お昼 一緒に食べる
Oh! Do you want to eat lunch with us?
遠慮しなくていいよ
No reason not to.
うん なら
Okay then.
え 柑菜 出かけたんですか
Kanna left?
In this rain?
こんな雨なのに
Yeah! She took all the vegetables we had too!
そうなのよ
うちにあった 野沢菜持ちだして
She's my daughter, but she's pretty weird.
我が娘ながら 変わった子よね
When she gets back, tell her I called.
じゃあ 戻ってきたら電話があったこと伝えてください
Thanks.
はい 失礼します
柑菜
Kanna...
You made sandwiches out of them?
野沢菜のサンドイッチ
I thought I might as well use them since I just got them.
せっかくだから 食材に使ってみました
This is...
これは
Is something wrong?
何か 間違ってる
うん うまいですよ
It's good.
It's kind of like vegetable dumplings.
ちょっと お焼きみたいですけど
Really?
そ そう
まあ グレープフルーツ丼を克服しましたからね
After your grapefruit rice bowl,
何でも来いって感じですよ
I think I can take on anything now.
You don't have to say it like that!
そ そんなことは言わないで
You're filming again?
また撮るの
She told me to film as much as I could.
たくさん取れって言われましたからね
Help us out here, Tanigawa.
谷川も 協力してよ
Try having a normal conversation together.
自然な感じで 会話してみて
A normal conversation might be kind of...
自然って言われても
Hey...
ねえ ほらほら
Come on.
Do you have any siblings, Tanigawa?
た 谷川さん 兄弟はいるの
No, I'm an only child.
一人子です
Tetsuro and I have been hanging out since we were kids, though,
でも 小さい頃から哲郎と一緒に遊んでて
so I was never really lonely.
寂しいとか無かったです
So you've known Ishigaki for a long time then?
石垣君とはそんなに古いんだ
He's kinda like a dumb little brother to me.
バカな弟みたいな感じです
Really? He seems more like the older brother type to me.
そう 私からすると 石垣君のほうがお兄さんに見えるけど
You just think that because he's tall.
背が高いから そう思うだけですよ
Do you have any siblings?
先輩こそ 兄弟は
A younger and an older sister.
姉と妹が
Three sisters! Sounds lovely!
三姉妹なんだ いいな
My family's all girls, so this is all new for me.
うちは女系家族で
だから ここに来て ちょっと新鮮なの
I guess this is what it feels like to have a man in the family.
男の人が家族にいると
こういう感じなのかなって
海人君を家族に例えると
Who would Kaito be in your family?
Her younger brother, right?
そりゃ弟だろう
うん そういう感じもあるけど
It does feel like that sometimes,
but he can be really dependable.
頼れるところもあるし
It's a bit hard to explain.
なんだろう うまく言えないかな
Just now.
あ 今の
That was good. Keep it going.
いいです そのまま そのまま
ええ 分かんないよ
I don't know how.
It's fine. Just act like you did before.
いいですって
ほら さっきの感じで
It's not that easy.
そんなこと言われても
Can I ask you something?
あの 先輩
You're here to study, right?
先輩って 留学してきてるんですよね
Yeah.
うん まあ
How long will you be here?
どのくらいここにいるんですか
Six months?
半年とか 一年とか
A year?
ああ それは
Well...
I'm sorry. I shouldn't've asked that.
ご ごめんなさい
私 余計なことを
No, it's okay. Don't worry about it.
うん うん いいの
気にしないで
Why...
私
Why did I...
どうして
Why did I ask that?
どうして あんなこと言っちゃったんだろう
あれじゃ 嫌なやつだ
That was a horrible thing to say.
I'm a terrible person.
ひどい やつだ
Shame on me.
みっともないやつだ
I'm not cute at all.
可愛くないんだ
私
何でここにいるのよ
Why are you here?
Coincidence.
偶然
美桜でしょう
Mio told you?
Perhaps.
まあ な
You went over to Kai's, right?
海んち 行ってたんだろう
勇気出したじゃん
That took courage.
I shouldn't've gone.
行かなきゃよかった
Why?
なんで
I shouldn't get involved.
入っていけないの
I get uneasy just watching the two of them talk.
もやもやするの
二人が話してるだけで
そう思う自分が嫌なの
I don't like when I get like that.
Just confess.
告っちゃえよ
海はさ まだ 先輩
Kai still hasn't...
I can't.
できない
Why?
なんで
I just can't.
できるわけないよ
もしダメだったら きっとギクシャクする
If it doesn't go well, things'll get awkward between us.
It'd be weird.
気まずくなる
I wouldn't be able to work on the movie with you guys if that happened.
これから 皆で映画を撮るのに
そうなったら 私 いけなくなる
I'd make Kaito uncomfortable.
海人君も きっと困る
So you're gonna keep sulking and not do anything about it?
なら 何もせずにもやもやし続けんの
人を好きになんないと 分かんないよ
You have no idea what it's like to be in love!
You have no idea...
哲郎には分かんないよ
そうだな 悪い
I guess so. Sorry.
I went too far.
私も言いすぎだ
Bus stop
Yamaura
Bus Kanto
Sorry.
ごめん
It finally let up.
やんだ やんだ よかった
Hey, Kanna...
あのさ 柑菜
I'll just act like nothing's wrong.
普通でいるんだ 私
We're all gonna have fun filming the movie over summer break.
夏休み 楽しく皆で映画を撮るの
映画を作って 学園祭なんかで発表して
We'll make the movie and show it at the school fair.
とにかく いつもの谷川柑菜でいるの
And I'll just continue being the usual Tanigawa Kanna.
そう決めたの
That's my decision.
Okay.
Let's go, Tetsuro.
ほら 行くよ 哲郎
Sure.
はい はい
I had no way of knowing what was going on back then.
あの時は そんなことがあったなんて
知りようもなく
谷川の気持ちも
Tanigawa's feelings...
Tetsuro's feelings...
哲郎の気持ちも
Kitahara's feelings...
北原の気持ちも
I had no way of knowing.
しりようがなく
あの時 僕は ある思いに囚われていて
Back then, I could only think about one thing.
"One day, she'll eventually be gone."
先輩がいつかいなくなる思いに
Hey.
よ よう
は 何やってんの
What are you doing?
い 入れてくれ
Let me in.
My arms are giving in.
腕が持たない
A lifesign?
生体反応
At this hour?
こんな時間に
What are you doing here so late?
何だよ こんな遅くに
Also, you should've just come in through the front door.
つうか 玄関から 入ってこいよ
My bad.
悪い 悪い
So what do you want?
で なんだよ
Kanna.
柑菜な
Tanigawa? She was here today.
谷川 谷川なら 今日うちに
She loves you.
あいつ
海が好きだぜ
Tanigawa Kanna...
谷川柑菜は
loves you,
霧島海人を
好きなんだ
Kirishima Kaito.
Episode Six
You've got a rival.
It's Okinawa!
Yeah, Okinawa.
It's so stimulating!
It's so enchanting!
This is awesome!
沖縄だ
ああ 沖縄だ
刺激的だ
ああ 魅惑的だ
ああ 堪んねえ